[{"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a33b", "question": "Which 1980's song includes the lyric \"Creatures crawl in search of blood. To terrorize y'alls neighborhood!\"?", "answer": "Thriller", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cafa", "question": "Poinephobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Punishment", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339af0", "question": "Who was the first person to say the words \"Live from New York, it's Saturday Night!\"?", "answer": "Chevy Chase", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fef66126ce05a3942286e75", "question": "What state inspired Joni Mitchell's \"Big Yellow Taxi\"?", "answer": "Hawaii", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59f9ba0c364247bf200fb894", "question": "Where do Grand Prix drivers put their cars at the beginning of a race?", "answer": "The Grid", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c55", "question": "What year saw the release of Whitney Houston's self-titled debut album?", "answer": "1985", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae58", "question": "The Minutemen fought during what war?", "answer": "American Revolution", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c673", "question": "Jonas Salk discovered a vaccine for what disease?", "answer": "Polio", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ad9e190e748bb36357acdf5", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"Murder on the Orient Express\"?", "answer": "Agatha Christie", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe76db3eec85e375820b2d7", "question": "What body of water is between Scotland and Denmark?", "answer": "The North Sea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c624", "question": "What shape is the milky way?", "answer": "Spiral", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad00", "question": "Whose death resulted in Elizabeth I becoming Queen?", "answer": "Mary I's", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58ab956686faa38a764be515", "question": "The Australian auto manufacturer, Holden, is a subsidiary of which US automotive brand?", "answer": "General Motors", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca1d", "question": "Almonds are members of what family?", "answer": "Rose", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab24", "question": "What island country is located east of Mozambique?", "answer": "Madagascar", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe7bdef877e98cb9777895b", "question": "What mountain is nicknamed the \"Savage Mountain\"?", "answer": "K-2", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339288", "question": "In the movie \"The Hunger Games\", what is Thresh's weapon of choice?", "answer": "A Scimitar", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399a8", "question": "What actor played Tom Hanks\u2019 buddy on \"Bosom Buddies\"?", "answer": "Peter Scolari", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a849", "question": "The historic district of Haight-Ashbury is located in what US city?", "answer": "San Francisco", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1f8", "question": "Telly Savalas played which TV detective?", "answer": "Kojak", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c416", "question": "How many horns did a triceratops have?", "answer": "Three", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fecd94eec223966ae8f88de", "question": "The big screen villain of which film required the use of 51 puppeteers?", "answer": "\"Little Shop of Horrors\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae37", "question": "What international award did President Theodore Roosevelt win in 1906?", "answer": "Nobel Peace Prize", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe93ad86bd93ce3a4e5f69c", "question": "Which theory explains the movement of the Earth's continents?", "answer": "Continental drift", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b86a", "question": "What is the Syrah grape called in Australia?", "answer": "Shiraz", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600780f8bd51d85e222ab646", "question": "What is the main visual element in Impressionist painting?", "answer": "They were interested in trying to capture the changing effects of light by using a more exact analysis of tone and color.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5b7ffb9a3a3a814d89068c67", "question": "Which singer and songwritter was born Farrokh Bulsara in 1946?", "answer": "Freddie Mercury", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3aa", "question": "Which famous painting was stolen from an Oslo museum in 1994?", "answer": "The Scream", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5f178122b8195c09b948d5c1", "question": "Who was the emperor of Ethiopia from 1930 to 1974?", "answer": "Haile Selassie", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c224", "question": "What is the Latin name for parsley?", "answer": "Petroselinum crispum", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3dd", "question": "Which is Europe's second largest island after Great Britain?", "answer": "Iceland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a905", "question": "What major river runs through Vienna?", "answer": "Danube", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ec5", "question": "What novel begins with \"It was a bright cold day in April, and the clocks were striking thirteen\"?", "answer": "Nineteen Eighty-four", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe7cb0a877e98cb97778a12", "question": "What nation does the island of Okinawa belong to?", "answer": "Japan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd27", "question": "In Europe, what are measured in \"Paris Points\"?", "answer": "Shoe sizes", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a647", "question": "What is the capital of the US state of Colorado?", "answer": "Denver", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fde4a7fc6c6b019850c9a76", "question": "Who was nicknamed the \"Iron Chancellor\" and known as the unifier of Germany?", "answer": "Otto Von Bismarck", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b75c", "question": "An insurance policy that is \"underwritten\" is one that has been what?", "answer": "Signed", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bcc", "question": "What is the name of Boy George's 1982 debut album?", "answer": "Kissing to be Clever", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffb60865dad637d903c882a", "question": "Off what country are the islands of Islay, Mull, and St. Kilda located?", "answer": "Scotland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fede0326ce05a3942286db7", "question": "Which is the only team in NFL history to have scored three touchdowns in less than a minute?", "answer": "New England Patriots", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a48c", "question": "What is the more common name for the collegiate church of St Peter in London?", "answer": "St. Paul's Cathedral", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2c1", "question": "In atmospheres, what is the equivalent of 760 milimeters of Mercury (mmHg)?", "answer": "1 atm", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5bb359eb2627b8fe95581be6", "question": "What nickname is printed on the official Wilson NFL football?", "answer": "The Duke", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391bb", "question": "What comedian was a drummer in the early days of the band Steely Dan?", "answer": "Chevy Chase", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a150", "question": "What did Dorothy's house land on in \"The Wizard of Oz\"?", "answer": "The Wicked Witch of the East", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0fe", "question": "The flowers of the curry tree are what color?", "answer": "White", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ab8", "question": "What animated series began as a video Christmas card the creator sent to 80 of his pals?", "answer": "South Park", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59f9bb96364247bf200fb8a5", "question": "What is a Karahi?", "answer": "A wok-like cooking pot", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c560", "question": "What is the common name for a \"nitrous oxide\"?", "answer": "Laughing gas", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b911", "question": "In the restaurant industry, what number does the kitchen commonly assign to an item that they've run out of?", "answer": "86", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bde1", "question": "What two consecutive signs of the Zodiac begin with the same letter?", "answer": "Scorpio and Sagittarius", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390eb", "question": "Which novelist created the character Helen West?", "answer": "Frances Fyfield", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59ded115ea2747c8aff16d2f", "question": "What is Thalassophobia the fear of?", "answer": "The Sea or sea travel", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f7d", "question": "Name Tin Tin's Canine Companion?", "answer": "Snowy\u00a0", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aca0", "question": "What European capital was first dubbed the City of Light in the 19th century?", "answer": "Paris", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ab99acb21a8909e5c332d23", "question": "The Kelvin scale is used to measure what?", "answer": "Temperature", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c249", "question": "How many liters are there in the U.S. gallon?", "answer": "3.78 liters", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fecc941ec223966ae8f8895", "question": "Which Hollywood legend did the film \"The Good, the Bad and the Ugly\" help catapult into stardom?", "answer": "Clint Eastwood", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5af25b0db63e5727cf5a4858", "question": "Which Canadian singer performed the song \"(Everything I Do) I Do It for You\"?", "answer": "Bryan Adams", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b464", "question": "Boxer John L. Sullivan is often recognized as the first what?", "answer": "Heavyweight Champion in gloved boxing", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c0e", "question": "How were composer George Gershwin and lyricist Ira Gershwin related?", "answer": "They were brothers", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5f4", "question": "Chevrolet sold a souped-up version of what car as the \"Z24\"?", "answer": "The Cavalier", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c15d", "question": "Which city is served by Schwechat airport?", "answer": "Vienna", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133926b", "question": "What singer was the first Latin-American actress to be paid $1 million for a movie role?", "answer": "Jennifer Lopez", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acbf", "question": "When did construction of the Berlin Wall begin?", "answer": "1961", "category": "history"}, {"id": "601214f563c99d48cd169ae4", "question": "Which researcher corrected Einstein's theory of a static universe?", "answer": "Edwin Hubble -- He concluded that the universe is actually expanding, something Einstein would admit was his own blunder.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5febaf887e83c707845b20fe", "question": "What is a natural loofah made of?", "answer": "A type of gourd", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab50", "question": "What is the capital of Slovenia?", "answer": "Ljubljana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58ec22f68dc25ca9e12ef62b", "question": "As whom was J\u00e1n Ludv\u00edk Hyman Binyamin Hoch better known?", "answer": "Robert Maxwell", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2f1", "question": "What five tastes can a human distinguish?", "answer": "Sweet, sour, salt, bitter, umami", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe698ff20565ad31a57c73e", "question": "The first-ever ticker-tape parade was thrown in celebration of what event?", "answer": "The dedication of the Statue of Liberty", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5febae9f7e83c707845b20f7", "question": "Which element is named after the Greek goddess of the moon?", "answer": "Selenium", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe6559aae7e414034b5aeb5", "question": "Which Norse god\u2019s image is Santa Claus partially based on?", "answer": "Odin", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe8aa0201dd7bf43be5e755", "question": "What goes up and down but remains in the same place?", "answer": "Stairs", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1ec", "question": "What is added to cognac and absinthe to make a Sazerac cocktail?", "answer": "Sugar cube and Peychaud's bitters", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5f30524f5aa2bc17b61b2ac9", "question": "What is the capital of Moldova?", "answer": "Chi\u0219in\u0103u", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fea4a46ff048f679a45abc2", "question": "What inventor first used the term \"Horse Power\"?", "answer": "James Watt", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4ad", "question": "What is usually added to tin to make solder?", "answer": "Lead", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390d0", "question": "Who wrote \"Auld Lang Syne\"?", "answer": "Robert Burns", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba65", "question": "In what year were Sea-\u00adMonkeys first marketed?", "answer": "1957", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339172", "question": "Mark Hamill was a voice actor for which popular early 90's superhero cartoon?", "answer": "Batman: The Animated Series", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff6667552a821ff76ae8af7", "question": "What miracle is Saint Valentine said to have performed shortly before his death?", "answer": "According to legend, Valentine restored the sight of his own jailer's daughter.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd66464a5bfecdd737e0854", "question": "When did scientists start giving hurricanes human names?", "answer": "1953", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae33", "question": "When did the War of 1812 actually begin?", "answer": "1812", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac04", "question": "Yaren is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Nauru", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a903", "question": "What major river runs through the city of London?", "answer": "Thames", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c92", "question": "What sci\u00adfi author is credited with coining the \"Three Laws of Robotics\"?", "answer": "Isaac Asimov", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "597cdacde347d002c297e4d8", "question": "What instrument did Yehudi Menuhin play?", "answer": "The violin", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3a2", "question": "Who was the first victim of the electric chair?", "answer": "William Francis Kemmler", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339337", "question": "How many children did Lucy and Desi have?", "answer": "Two", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a08b", "question": "Which two teams automatically qualified for the 1998 soccer World Cup?", "answer": "France and Brazil", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1e7", "question": "Which US president lived in Peacefield?", "answer": "John Adams", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe7bf10877e98cb97778965", "question": "What is the smallest country in South America?", "answer": "Suriname", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5a162a47f01ec323f8491722", "question": "What are the separators on a guitar neck called?", "answer": "Frets", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0b7", "question": "Which Actor played Chachi Arcola on the TV show \"Happy Days\"?", "answer": "Scott Baio", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb2e", "question": "In 1997, who became the first racecar driver to be featured on the front of a Wheaties box?", "answer": "Dale Earnhardt", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9f1", "question": "In which Mediterranean Sea are the Cyclades islands?", "answer": "The Aegean", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6014c7cffbde8045e48466c8", "question": "Masses are to Newton's Gravitational Law as charges are to what?", "answer": "Coulomb's Law", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e3a", "question": "What children's classic first chapter is titled \"Mrs. Rachel Lynde Is Surprised\"?", "answer": "Anne of Green Gables", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c176", "question": "What type of instrument is a Celesta?", "answer": "Keyboard", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133962c", "question": "In what movie does Cary Grant play a ghost?", "answer": "Topper", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4ac", "question": "What two states border Lake Champlain?", "answer": "New York and Vermont", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5b6992eee762b54eb9be9427", "question": "What year saw the start of Prohibition in the United States?", "answer": "1920", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339686", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", what is Mr. Burns' first name?", "answer": "Charles", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe734eaeec85e375820b23f", "question": "Who served as Hitler's Deputy Fuhrer from 1933 to 1941?", "answer": "Rudolph Hess", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c57d", "question": "What is the common term for an injury to the neck caused by a jerk of the head?", "answer": "Whiplash", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5e6", "question": "Which missionary was the first European to discover Victoria Falls?", "answer": "David Livingstone", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff2592731a458464a93c46a", "question": "In what year was the NERF football created?", "answer": "1972 by former Minnesota Vikings' kicker Fred Cox", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5a4a991561d1b4d384d5d696", "question": "How long was the TV show \"Gunsmoke\" between 1955 and 1961?", "answer": "30 minutes", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5af24be2844f4236002b95b1", "question": "How many countries does Afghanistan border?", "answer": "6", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c709", "question": "Retinol is another name for what Vitamin?", "answer": "A", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58d115314fea7fe947a22264", "question": "Who produced the Beatles' \"Sgt. Pepper's Lonely Hearts Club Band\" album?", "answer": "George Martin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59f9b9f6364247bf200fb893", "question": "What is a \"Shoal\"?", "answer": "A group of fish", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2b5", "question": "Which of Henry VIII's wives may never have slept with him?", "answer": "Anne of Cleves", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b954", "question": "In what city is the Kentucky Derby held every year?", "answer": "Louisville", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59bb29c1c9bff04efae6d759", "question": "Whose novels include \"The Joy Luck Club\" and \"The Kitchen God's Wife\"?", "answer": "Amy Tan's", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff08fd2e662d71a53650fb2", "question": "Which philosophical movement helped inspire the American Revolution?", "answer": "The Enlightenment -- It included great leaps in philosophical thought \u2014 including ideas about democracy, the social contract, and freedom.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "601218b963c99d48cd169af7", "question": "In Swedish, what is \"entrance\" and \"driveway\", respectively?", "answer": "\"Infart\" and \"Uppfart\"", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bac", "question": "Which two dimensional character issued these orders, \"Off with her head\"?", "answer": "The Queen of Hearts", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59bb28a4c9bff04efae6d752", "question": "What massively successful novel did Mario Puzo publish in 1969?", "answer": "The Godfather", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b96e", "question": "How many cards comprise a pack of Tarot cards?", "answer": "78", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113394df", "question": "What was the name of the family in \"One Man's Family\" TV show?", "answer": "The Barbours", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd18c3129d03ab85b632b33", "question": "Who first said, \"Genius is one percent inspiration, ninety-nine percent perspiration\"?", "answer": "Thomas Edison", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe65633ae7e414034b5aec3", "question": "Who was Japan's supreme military leader during World War II?", "answer": "T\u014dj\u014d Hideki", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afe7", "question": "Which US president was born in Tampico, Illinois?", "answer": "Ronald Reagan", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fecc101ec223966ae8f8863", "question": "The 2016 Cavaliers defeated which NBA team to win Cleveland\u2019s first title?", "answer": "Golden State Warriors", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5f164d5df9b80650dbe7f931", "question": "What year did Daniel Defoe first publish the novel \"Robinson Crusoe\"?", "answer": "1719", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399ac", "question": "Blues legend McKinley Morganfield was better known by what name?", "answer": "Muddy Waters", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff514e3ff04d658268c92e5", "question": "What actor was one of the most decorated American combat soldiers of World War II?", "answer": "Audie Murphy\u00a0received every military combat award for valor available from the U.S. Army, including the Medal of Honor.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd81dced0de9af39e9d4693", "question": "What state elected a former pro wrestler as its governor?", "answer": "Minnesota", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58f5655f33a95c66dc4fe756", "question": "What does a phrenologist measure?", "answer": "Skulls", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6015f839fe83fe1f2a824c2a", "question": "The \"St. Valentine's Day Massacre\" was perpetrated by which historical figure?", "answer": "Al Capone ordered the murders on February 14, 1929, but the primary target got away.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aea8", "question": "Which French King Louis was called the Sun King?", "answer": "Louis XIV", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fdaba4a0b8cce1e6fda7057", "question": "What cheese's name literally means \"recooked\" in Italian?", "answer": "Ricotta", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ecd", "question": "Who hosted the TV show \"This Old House\" for the first ten seasons?", "answer": "Bob Vila", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b993", "question": "What number was retired by the Chicago Bulls to honor Michael Jordan?", "answer": "23", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fef5af46ce05a3942286e0f", "question": "In the film \"One Flew Over the Cuckoo's Nest,\" what is R. P. McMurphy's first name?", "answer": "Randle", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fed2c08ec223966ae8f8915", "question": "What Vin Diesel film did David Twohy direct?", "answer": "\"The Chronicles Of Riddick\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59a1a4a012f2a7826b9b8732", "question": "In the movie \"Spaceballs\" what does the bumper sticker say on the back of Lonestar's ship?", "answer": "I love Uranus", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a19", "question": "What UK band had a #1 hit in 1981 with the song \"Don\u2019t You Want Me\"?", "answer": "Human League", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59008f0ecf842fa4c4ba96b7", "question": "What did William H. Seward buy from Russia in 1867?", "answer": "Alaska", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b199", "question": "What Germany city hosted the 1972 Olympic games?", "answer": "Munich", "category": "history"}, {"id": "600cc0c66de0eb824d4052db", "question": "In which mountain range can you find Australia\u2019s tallest peak?", "answer": "Australian Alps -- It is covered in ski resorts and in the summer, many people hike to its tallest peak, Mount Kosciuszko.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1eb", "question": "What failed IBM computer was advertised by a Charlie Chaplin impersonator?", "answer": "The PCjr", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ad9e209e748bb36357acdf8", "question": "What was Alfred Hitchcock\u2019s first American made film?", "answer": "Rebecca", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe3e8c738e4e5d4832e630b", "question": "For what 1924 crime were Nathan Leopold, Jr. and Richard Loeb arrested?", "answer": "Murder", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd81c38d0de9af39e9d4681", "question": "What was the first NASA Mars rover named?", "answer": "Sojourner", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a657", "question": "The Red River flows into what river?", "answer": "Mississippi River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6014c47efbde8045e484669c", "question": "What are the only large cats that roar together as a group?", "answer": "Lions -- Used to mark territories, a pride of lions can be heard from 5 miles away.  Even the young cubs will join in the roaring.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa2d", "question": "What's the capital of Comoros?", "answer": "Moroni", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4d0", "question": "In relation to the Halloween holiday, what is the archaic meaning of the word \"Hallow\"?", "answer": "Saint", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fecca05ec223966ae8f8897", "question": "What is the name of the alien race who were the adoptive parents of Samus in the \"Metroid\" franchise?", "answer": "The Chozo", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f55", "question": "What James Joyce story collection begins with \"The Sisters\" and ends with \"The Dead\"?", "answer": "Dubliners", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ffa52a7c73aa70ea0b70b1c", "question": "Frankenmuth, a U.S. city nicknamed \"Little Bavaria\", is located in what state?", "answer": "Michigan (It is a German-style town in Saginaw County. It is well known for its hotels and old-style German buildings.)", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa1a", "question": "What's the opposite of the Orient?", "answer": "The Occident", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58d07772870e6f05ba600864", "question": "What was astronaut Edwin Eugene Aldrin Jr.'s nickname?", "answer": "Buzz", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b239", "question": "What royal subject married Grace Kelly?", "answer": "Rainier III of Monaco", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aefd", "question": "What did explorer Robert Peary attempt to reach in 1909?", "answer": "The North Pole", "category": "history"}, {"id": "60121b8063c99d48cd169b0e", "question": "\"Cartomancy\" tells the future using what?", "answer": "Playing cards -- Like tarot reading, cartomancy involves the use of cards. Instead of using tarot cards, playing cards are used.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fef61266ce05a3942286e50", "question": "The Simpsons\" got its start as filler material on which show?", "answer": "\"Tbe Tracy Ullman Show\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fa4", "question": "Poseidon was the Greek god of what?", "answer": "Sea", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc25", "question": "In what year was Wikipedia officially launched?", "answer": "2001", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133970d", "question": "Actor Jason Lee was a professional in which sport?", "answer": "Skateboarding", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8f07b01dd7bf43be5e7fc", "question": "What is missing in a New England milkshake?", "answer": "Ice cream", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f88", "question": "Who is the author of the book \"Spark Joy\"?", "answer": "Marie Kondo", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59068190ff9c0647b50a8095", "question": "Which Gabor sister, who passed away in December of 2016, was crowned Miss Hungary in 1936?", "answer": "Zsa Zsa Gabor", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b715", "question": "The album, Sacred Arias was released by what blind Italian tenor?", "answer": "Andrea Bocelli", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0d7", "question": "Who won an Oscar for his role in the film 'The Fugitive\"?", "answer": "Tommy Lee Jones", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133897b", "question": "In what book did Rudyard Kipling introduce readers to a mongoose named Rikki Tikki Tavi?", "answer": "The Jungle Book", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59071bf03745b36be73039c6", "question": "What meat is illegal in the Chew comics universe?", "answer": "Chicken", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c419", "question": "What is a rhino horn made of?", "answer": "Keratin", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397f6", "question": "Which country and western singer is best remembered for her recording of \"Crazy\"?", "answer": "Patsy Cline", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc17", "question": "What organization was formed to replace \"The League of Nations\"?", "answer": "United Nations", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339916", "question": "What was the name of Vince Vaughn\u2019s gymnasium in \u201cDodgeball: A True Underdog Story\u201d?", "answer": "Average Joe's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7c873877e98cb977789e5", "question": "Where can you visit a museum devoted to failed inventions?", "answer": "Austria", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6e1", "question": "What is the more common name for the human tympanic membrane?", "answer": "Eardrum", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aaf8", "question": "N'Djamena is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Chad", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339dc9", "question": "What double-word song title was a hit single by Naked Eyes?", "answer": "Promises, Promises", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b69f", "question": "What type of berry was once believed to cause birthmarks when eaten by pregnant women?", "answer": "Strawberry", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fdc1277469bb8041d07a07c", "question": "Vampires are typically known for turning into which animal?", "answer": "Bat", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad97", "question": "Who succeeded Spiro Agnew as vice president of the United States?", "answer": "Gerald Ford", "category": "history"}, {"id": "60078c5a0eee65b76b9f2672", "question": "Who became vice president of the U.S. after President Nixon resigned?", "answer": "Nelson Aldrich Rockefeller", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b413", "question": "In what year was nylon first synthesized?", "answer": "1935", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fc2f74ccee580c7f8fd1e5e", "question": "In underwater diving, what does SCUBA stand for?", "answer": "Self-Contained Underwater Breathing Apparatus", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b155", "question": "What year was Princess Diana born?", "answer": "1961", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59f9b7a7364247bf200fb874", "question": "Who had a hit in 1988 with the song \"I Get Weak\"?", "answer": "Belinda Carlisle", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "60077f9fbd51d85e222ab63e", "question": "What late 19th-century French painter was known for his pictures of ballet dancers?", "answer": "Edgar Degas is acknowledged as the master of drawing human figures in motion. The female ballet dancer became his favorite theme.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bd4", "question": "According to legend, what was the name of the Roman slave who removed a thorn from the lion's foot?", "answer": "Androcles", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b78", "question": "Who wrote the play \"Cat on a Hot Tin Roof\"?", "answer": "Tennessee Williams", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6ba", "question": "Which planet orbits the Sun the quickest?", "answer": "Mercury", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d3a", "question": "What newspaper does Superman work for?", "answer": "The Daily Planet", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c80e", "question": "What optical component is named for the bean whose shape it resembles?", "answer": "Lens", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af70", "question": "Which US president was born in Milton, Massachusetts?", "answer": "George Bush Sr.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d9c", "question": "Who played the role of the US president in the movie \"Dr. Strangelove\"?", "answer": "Peter Sellers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd2d7af2596a59cbdfbd3b9", "question": "Who is credited with the legend of the Lost City of Atlantis?", "answer": "Plato", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a15e", "question": "What is the occupation of Mary Poppins?", "answer": "Nanny", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6016015dfe83fe1f2a824c5e", "question": "Traditional May Day celebrations in Germany and surrounding nations was tied-in with the recognition of which saint?", "answer": "Saint Walpurgis", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59029d97cad1ec93f27df750", "question": "What company\u2019s tea shipment was destroyed during the Boston Tea Party in 1773?", "answer": "East India Company", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b19e", "question": "What year did the construction of the Berlin Wall start?", "answer": "1961", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba4b", "question": "What were the Portsmouth Spartans renamed after the team was moved to Detroit?", "answer": "Detroit Lions", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bbd", "question": "What popular designer was responsible for the wardrobe of \"The Fifth Element\"?", "answer": "Jean Paul Gaultier", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff6668652a821ff76ae8af8", "question": "What is the name of the wood Noah used in building his ark?", "answer": "Gopher wood", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff51638ff04d658268c92ee", "question": "What queen defeated and killed Cyrus the Great of Persia?", "answer": "Tomyris, a Massagetean ruler, led her armies against an attack by Cyrus the Great of the Achaemenid in 530 BC.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afae", "question": "What first ran from Paddington to Farringdon Street in 1863?", "answer": "The London Underground", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133918e", "question": "Who is smarter than the average bear?", "answer": "Yogi Bear", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7f7", "question": "On what continent is the Balkan Peninsula?", "answer": "Europe", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe1f144145fb29466707391", "question": "What is an Alsace wine blended from different kinds of grapes called?", "answer": "Edelzwicker", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff0b8d3e662d71a53651028", "question": "The \"clocks were striking thirteen\" at the start of which dystopian novel?", "answer": "1984", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5a9e96e47ccba3ffe45786f3", "question": "A 25 to 31 mph wind on the Beaufort scale is called what?", "answer": "Strong breeze", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fefa9296ce05a3942286edc", "question": "What musical did the song \"We Need a Little Christmas\" originate from?", "answer": "Mame", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4b3", "question": "Sharpshooter Phoebe Ann Mosey was better known as who?", "answer": "Annie Oakley", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af28", "question": "Who founded the city of Singapore?", "answer": "Stamford Raffles", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8dd", "question": "The Yellow River is what country's second longest?", "answer": "China's", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59049c60cf93664eb10486a6", "question": "What is the fear of the number 13 known as?", "answer": "Triskaidekaphobia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a4", "question": "What city is the TV show \"Sex and the City\" based in?", "answer": "New York", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c86a", "question": "What is the more common name for benzoic sulfinide?", "answer": "Saccharin", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339217", "question": "What Stealers Wheel hit is heard in the movie \"Reservoir Dogs\"?", "answer": "Stuck in the Middle with You", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c720", "question": "What part of the human body experiences different growth rates called anagen, catagen, and telogen?", "answer": "The hair", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7fa", "question": "At which university was the beverage Gatorade developed?", "answer": "University of Florida", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8ab", "question": "In what city would you find Battery Park?", "answer": "New York City", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a41", "question": "What \"couple\" would be known as Fischbacher and Horn if they went by their last names?", "answer": "Siegfried & Roy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59049ca0cf93664eb10486a8", "question": "Which famous rapper died on Friday, September 13, 1996?", "answer": "Tupac Shakur", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133938b", "question": "What did Vern bring for the trip in the movie \"Stand By Me\"?", "answer": "A comb", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fedda1c6ce05a3942286d81", "question": "Red described geology as the study of what in the movie \"The Shawshank Redemption\"?", "answer": "Red remarked that geology is the study of time and pressure.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acf3", "question": "What Christian sect did a Huguenot belong to?", "answer": "Protestant", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a607", "question": "In which country would you find the state of Tabasco?", "answer": "Mexico", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58f16a39f7c52aae91cc07d9", "question": "Who is the main character is Shakespeare's \"The Tempest\"?", "answer": "Prospero", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c9d", "question": "How did Scarlett and Rhett\u2019s daughter die, in \"Gone with the Wind\"?", "answer": "Fell off a horse", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2e6", "question": "Where is the skeleton of a spider located?", "answer": "On the outside of the body", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af1e", "question": "Which royal palace was damaged by fire in 1986?", "answer": "Hampton Court Palace", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5af25190b63e5727cf5a4839", "question": "By what name do Germans refer to Austria?", "answer": "\u04e6sterreich", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391ad", "question": "Who recorded the international hit single \"Poker Face\" in 2008?", "answer": "Lady Gaga", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fbaebc10738315b1fb74e2c", "question": "What Shakesperian play involves love between a Roman Soldier and the Queen of Egypt?", "answer": "Antony and Cleopatra", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ab1b2b64fda37788a9a1dbd", "question": "What is the fear of darkness called?", "answer": "Scotophobia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338dab", "question": "Who satirized the threat of nuclear was in \"The Butter Battle Book\"?", "answer": "Dr. Seuss", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b613", "question": "Near which city is US' only nuclear assembly and disassembly site located?", "answer": "Amarillo, Texas", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e2", "question": "What year was the first book of the \"Bourne Trilogy\" series first published?", "answer": "1980", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff0af93e662d71a53650fc0", "question": "Joseph Pulitzer founded a school of journalism at which university?", "answer": "Columbia", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8ec", "question": "What is the standard tuning of a guitar?", "answer": "E A D G B E", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339609", "question": "What was Tom Cruise's call sign in the 1986 movie \"Top Gun\"?", "answer": "Maverick", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015fbaefe83fe1f2a824c3b", "question": "Some Irish old stories suggest that St. Patrick's walking stick once miraculously tranformed into what object?", "answer": "There are stories that say he stuck his ash walking stick in the ground that he wanted to evangelize. It grew into a tree.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6017349944491cbd7c5a1781", "question": "What is he maximum number of years a US president can serve in office?", "answer": "Ten years -- If he or she inherited the office after a president died or was removed with two years or less remaining in the term, he can serve two more full terms. Otherwise they are limited to one full term.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba0e", "question": "What position did Babe Ruth play when he first joined the Boston Red Sox in 1914?", "answer": "Pitcher", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf00", "question": "In which athletics event are competitors known as either \"Spinners\" or \"Shifters''?", "answer": "Shot Putt", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a964", "question": "Parts of what Chilean desert have gone four hundred years without rainfall?", "answer": "The Atacama", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a8e", "question": "What was the name of Paul McCartney's backup group from 1971 to 1981?", "answer": "Wings", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3b2", "question": "What is the heaviest breed of bear?", "answer": "Polar bear", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae8e", "question": "What is James Bowie reported to have dropped into a well at the Alamo?", "answer": "Gold", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe7c1de877e98cb9777897f", "question": "What was the first cave in the world to be designated a national park?", "answer": "Wind Cave", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395bc", "question": "In The Simpsons, how do Homer and Marge find out that Bart ran away on Thanksgiving?", "answer": "They see him on TV", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea39f9ff048f679a45ab29", "question": "What element is named after the Greek word for green?", "answer": "Chlorine", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5f9f492aaf848b908361b87a", "question": "Which legume can be processed to make dynamite?", "answer": "Peanuts", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fefa4f86ce05a3942286eba", "question": "What duo first recorded the song \"Careless Whisper\"?", "answer": "Wham!", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c283", "question": "How often are brain cells replaced?", "answer": "Never", "category": "science"}, {"id": "596dfa93cf3977a46e7ce447", "question": "The Statue of Liberty was a gift resulting from the diplomatic relationship between the United States and what country?", "answer": "France", "category": "history"}]